<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>YosysHQ Blog</title>
        <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content on YosysHQ Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 15:35:40 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.yosyshq.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>New pricing for small companies</title>
        <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/pricing-for-small-companies/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 15:35:40 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/pricing-for-small-companies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;YosysHQ are pleased to announce a new pricing option for small companies with one full time engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For just €500 per month (excl. VAT), you can get our ‘Solo bundle’:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 nodes of TabbyCAD Suite, offering industry compatible language support and our formal verification tools and verification IP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited number of users/processes per node. (Up to 32 CPUs per node.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not time limited, use in your continuous integration systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support that includes potential for custom work and access to our technical team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For two full time engineers, we have our ‘Solo bundle plus’ which adds another 2 TabbyCAD nodes for an additional €400 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have competitive prices for larger teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an evaluation license, or to discuss your requirements further please contact us at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:contact@yosyshq.com&#34; &gt;contact@yosyshq.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>App Note 109</title>
        <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 12:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This Application Note was written with the intention of showing a brief introduction to SVA, and is definitely not a substitute for extensive training. To learn more about formal verification and SVA, it is recommended to book the course given by the FPV specialists at YosysHQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A brief history of SystemVerilog Assertions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SVA layers definition and examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assertion types, sequential property operators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A short description of liveness and safety properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical examples using the sequence builder module written by our CTO Claire Xen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yosyshq.readthedocs.io/projects/ap109&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://yosyshq.readthedocs.io/projects/ap109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to give us feedback and suggest new topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>App Note 120</title>
        <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:04:45 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time people have asked us for quality long form content that shows how to
get the best from our formal tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have started a series of app notes, with the first being about cover and witness for SVA properties. Otherwise known as &amp;lsquo;Am I testing what I think I&amp;rsquo;m testing&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What You will learn in this app note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default clocking and default disable declarations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequences and cycle delays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlapping and non-overlapping implication syntax and semantic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak precondition cover and witness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to apply that to a practical HDL code example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yosyshq.readthedocs.io/projects/ap120&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://yosyshq.readthedocs.io/projects/ap120&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to give us feedback and suggest new topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.yosyshq.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YosysHQ.com&lt;/a&gt; is the new home for the team maintaining Yosys and the related Open Source EDA projects, and the commercial products and services we offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team is led by N. Engelhardt as CEO, Claire Wolf as CTO, and Matt Venn as CSO. We are looking to work with more people, so feel free to contact us: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:contact@yosyshq.com&#34; &gt;contact@yosyshq.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabby CAD Suite is a bundle of our well-known Open Source EDA software packages, combined with additional components that allow seamless integration of our tools in typical industrial digital design environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide support and training for users of our Tabby CAD Suite package and for developers building their work on top of our open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we welcome opportunities to get involved with new projects large and small. We are looking to grow our collaborations with industry and academic partners on improving and expanding our synthesis, place and route, and formal verification flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to a positive relationship with the Open Source EDA community and external partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you visit our website &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.yosyshq.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;www.yosyshq.com&lt;/a&gt; and send us an email or tweet at us &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yosyshq&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;@YosysHQ&lt;/a&gt; to say hi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
