<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>YosysHQ Blog</title>
        <link>https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content on YosysHQ Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:04:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>App Note 120</title>
        <link>https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/p/app-note-120/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:04:45 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/p/app-note-120/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time people have asked us for quality long form content that shows how to
get the best from our formal tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have started a series of app notes, with the first being about cover and witness for SVA properties. Otherwise known as &amp;lsquo;Am I testing what I think I&amp;rsquo;m testing&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What You will learn in this app note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default clocking and default disable declarations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequences and cycle delays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlapping and non-overlapping implication syntax and semantic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak precondition cover and witness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to apply that to a practical HDL code example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yosyshq-subprj-doc.readthedocs.io/projects/weak_precond_and_witness/en/latest/&#34;&gt;https://yosyshq-subprj-doc.readthedocs.io/projects/weak_precond_and_witness/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to give us feedback and suggest new topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Press Release</title>
        <link>https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/p/press-release/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yosyshq-gmbh.github.io/p/press-release/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.yosyshq.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YosysHQ.com&lt;/a&gt; is the new home for the team maintaining Yosys and the related Open Source EDA projects, and the commercial products and services we offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team is led by N. Engelhardt as CEO, Claire Wolf as CTO, and Matt Venn as CSO. We are looking to work with more people, so feel free to contact us: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@yosyshq.com&#34;&gt;contact@yosyshq.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabby CAD Suite is a bundle of our well-known Open Source EDA software packages, combined with additional components that allow seamless integration of our tools in typical industrial digital design environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide support and training for users of our Tabby CAD Suite package and for developers building their work on top of our open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we welcome opportunities to get involved with new projects large and small. We are looking to grow our collaborations with industry and academic partners on improving and expanding our synthesis, place and route, and formal verification flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to a positive relationship with the Open Source EDA community and external partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you visit our website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yosyshq.com&#34;&gt;www.yosyshq.com&lt;/a&gt; and send us an email or tweet at us &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yosyshq&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;@YosysHQ&lt;/a&gt; to say hi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
