<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>release notes on YosysHQ Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/release-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in release notes on YosysHQ Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20221205 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221205-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221205-released/</guid>
      <description>The December release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download. Notable changes in this version include:
We have improved support for SystemVerilog config elements. You can now have multiple configurations defined, and select which configuration to elaborate with verific -import &amp;amp;lt;configname&amp;gt;. We are working on improving the TCL integration in Yosys. There is now an interactive TCL shell mode: use yosys -C to enter the TCL shell. You can now also use the following command to get the output of a command returned to TCL without the use of an intermediate file: set command_output [yosys tee -s result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20221108 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221108-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221108-released/</guid>
      <description>The November release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download. Notable changes in this version include:
We have experimentally added support for EDIF and Liberty verific parsers. They can be used either with the verific [-liberty|-edif] or the read [-liberty|-edif] command. We are evaluating whether it is of interest for us to keep these long-term, so please let us know if you use them and what your experience is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20221011 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221011-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20221011-released/</guid>
      <description>The October release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
The read and verific commands now support here-documents in scripts, the same way as read_verilog. This is useful e.g. to have small self-contained tests in a single file such as:
read -sv &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOT module top(input clk, output reg [1:0] q); wire [1:0] x = 2&#39;b10; always @(posedge clk) q &amp;lt;= x &amp;amp; 2&#39;b11; endmodule EOT prep -top top sim -clock clk -n 1 -w top select -assert-count 1 a:init=2&#39;b10 top/q %i </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220906 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220906-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220906-released/</guid>
      <description>The September release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
SBY SBY now runs multiple tasks in parallel. Additionally it now limits the number of concurrently running subprocesses to the available number of cores. The &amp;ndash;sequential command line option allows you to opt out of running tasks in parallel and the -j N option sets the limit of concurrent subprocesses to N instead of the default. All this is optionally integrated with the make jobserver protocol to enforce the concurrent process limit across other processes launched by make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220805 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220805-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220805-released/</guid>
      <description>The August release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
SBY SBY now uses a more precise logic loop analysis, removing the need to run simplemap on coarse-grain cells that re-use parts of a signal. In other YosysHQ news Since we introduced the new autotune option, we’ve now written up a blogpost with an example on how to get started. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220706 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220706-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220706-released/</guid>
      <description>The July release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
SBY An autotune function! This won’t fix your singing, but we hope it will help you to choose a good solver for your application. Please check the new documentation here to get started. Please let us know if you try the new feature. We will write a blogpost about it for the next newsletter. In other YosysHQ news Since tribuf support was added in May, we wrote a short blogpost about Matt’s use of it for his latest ASIC submission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220610 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220610-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220610-released/</guid>
      <description>The June release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
Yosys A big overhaul of memory inference in Yosys. The new pass memory_libmap supports a wider variety of memory patterns, such as single-port memories or asymmetric memories. It will also strictly respect verilog semantics in cases of address collision, adding emulation circuitry to ensure the synthesized behavior matches simulation. To omit the emulation circuitry even in cases where it is required for correctness, you can add the (* no_rw_check *) attribute to the array declaration of the memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220512 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220512-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220512-released/</guid>
      <description>The May release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
SBY The tribuf pass now supports a -formal option that converts inferred tri-state buffers within a module into equivalent non-tri-state logic for formal verification. It automatically adds assertions that detect multiple drivers driving the same net simultaneously. (When using tri-state I/O across modules, tribuf -formal should be preceded by a flatten pass). Several changes in the handling of x values during formal verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabby CAD Suite version 20220406 released!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220406-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/tabby-cad-suite-version-20220406-released/</guid>
      <description>The April release of Tabby CAD Suite is now available for download.
Yosys The sim command now allows co-simulation with stimulus values from aiger and btor2 witness files as well as traces in VCD or FST format. Co-simulation of designs with multiple clock domains was improved. SBY The --keep-going option was added to the smtbmc engine. With this option, the solver will continue to check the remaining properties even after an assertion fails.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
