<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on YosysHQ Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on YosysHQ Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.yosyshq.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Asynchronous Load Flip-Flops Should Be Avoided</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/async-load-ff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/async-load-ff/</guid>
      <description>Code: https://github.com/YosysHQ-Docs/Blog-Async-Load-FFs
Part 1: The Bad News We have recently added support for asynchronous load flip-flops to Yosys for a customer project. However, we consider this a problematic feature in a (System-)Verilog synthesis tool, and thus I’d like to take this opportunity to explain why one should avoid using asynchronous load flip-flops in new (System-)Verilog designs.
What are asynchronous load flip-flops An asynchronous load flip-flop is a type of flip-flop with asynchronous reset for which the reset value is not a compile-time / synthesis-time constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New pricing for small companies</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/pricing-for-small-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 15:35:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/pricing-for-small-companies/</guid>
      <description>YosysHQ are pleased to announce a new pricing option for small companies with one full time engineer.
For just €500 per month (excl. VAT), you can get our ‘Solo bundle’:
 2 nodes of TabbyCAD Suite, offering industry compatible language support and our formal verification tools and verification IP. Unlimited number of users/processes per node. (Up to 32 CPUs per node.) Not time limited, use in your continuous integration systems. Support that includes potential for custom work and access to our technical team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Note 109</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 12:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</guid>
      <description>This Application Note was written with the intention of showing a brief introduction to SVA, and is definitely not a substitute for extensive training. To learn more about formal verification and SVA, it is recommended to book the course given by the FPV specialists at YosysHQ.
 A brief history of SystemVerilog Assertions SVA layers definition and examples Assertion types, sequential property operators A short description of liveness and safety properties Practical examples using the sequence builder module written by our CTO Claire Xen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Note 120</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:04:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</guid>
      <description>For a long time people have asked us for quality long form content that shows how to get the best from our formal tools.
We have started a series of app notes, with the first being about cover and witness for SVA properties. Otherwise known as &amp;lsquo;Am I testing what I think I&amp;rsquo;m testing&amp;rsquo;!
What You will learn in this app note:
 Default clocking and default disable declarations Sequences and cycle delays Overlapping and non-overlapping implication syntax and semantic Weak precondition cover and witness How to apply that to a practical HDL code example  https://yosyshq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</guid>
      <description>YosysHQ.com is the new home for the team maintaining Yosys and the related Open Source EDA projects, and the commercial products and services we offer.
Our team is led by N. Engelhardt as CEO, Claire Wolf as CTO, and Matt Venn as CSO. We are looking to work with more people, so feel free to contact us: contact@yosyshq.com
Tabby CAD Suite is a bundle of our well-known Open Source EDA software packages, combined with additional components that allow seamless integration of our tools in typical industrial digital design environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
