<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on YosysHQ Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on YosysHQ Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:38:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teodor-Dumitru and the Complexity of Adder Implementations in Hardware</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/optimising-adders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:38:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/optimising-adders/</guid>
      <description>Teodor-Dumitru Ene will be presenting his work on adder optimisations, he&amp;rsquo;ll be covering:
 Prefix sums His research Adder-specific quirks and optimizations Future goals Questions!  Please join us:
 Tuesday, 10 May · 17:30 – 18:30 CEST Streaming on youtube  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Silicon with Yosys</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/open-source-silicon-with-yosys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:23:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/open-source-silicon-with-yosys/</guid>
      <description>Yosys is probably best known for providing synthesis for FPGA targets, but it&amp;rsquo;s a very flexible tool capable of a lot more.
OpenLane, SiliconCompiler and Coriolis2 are 3 examples of open source ASIC flows, which has been an active field of development over the last year.
We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to see our tools get used in the first Google sponsored tapeouts, helping to make the world&amp;rsquo;s first chips made with an open source PDK, and open source all the way down to the designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/hello/</guid>
      <description>YosysHQ.com is the new home for the team maintaining Yosys and the related Open Source EDA projects, and the commercial products and services we offer.
Our team is led by N. Engelhardt as CEO, Claire Wolf as CTO, and Matt Venn as CSO. We are looking to work with more people, so feel free to contact us: contact@yosyshq.com
Tabby CAD Suite is a bundle of our well-known Open Source EDA software packages, combined with additional components that allow seamless integration of our tools in typical industrial digital design environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
