<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>app note on YosysHQ Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/app-note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in app note on YosysHQ Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 12:37:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.yosyshq.com/tags/app-note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>App Note 109</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 12:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap109/</guid>
      <description>This Application Note was written with the intention of showing a brief introduction to SVA, and is definitely not a substitute for extensive training. To learn more about formal verification and SVA, it is recommended to book the course given by the FPV specialists at YosysHQ.&#xA;A brief history of SystemVerilog Assertions SVA layers definition and examples Assertion types, sequential property operators A short description of liveness and safety properties Practical examples using the sequence builder module written by our CTO Claire Xen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>App Note 120</title>
      <link>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:04:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.yosyshq.com/p/ap120/</guid>
      <description>For a long time people have asked us for quality long form content that shows how to get the best from our formal tools.&#xA;We have started a series of app notes, with the first being about cover and witness for SVA properties. Otherwise known as &amp;lsquo;Am I testing what I think I&amp;rsquo;m testing&amp;rsquo;!&#xA;What You will learn in this app note:&#xA;Default clocking and default disable declarations Sequences and cycle delays Overlapping and non-overlapping implication syntax and semantic Weak precondition cover and witness How to apply that to a practical HDL code example https://yosyshq.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
